# Sampath Medarametla

<u>reachtosampath@gmail.com</u> • +1 (270) 226-4777 github.com/iamSampath • linkedin.com/in/smedarametla

## **Summary Statement**

Accomplished senior software engineer and agile team lead with masters in information systems and 5+ years' experience at a top e-commerce company. Expertise in framework, Software development and Project Management with proven record of handling and leading international teams.

# **Work Experience**

## **Deliverables Manager, Customer support tech tools**

eBay, San Jose, CA

October 2021 – Present

- Coordinated development and quality engineering teams towards the required project deliverables for the releases
- Facilitated the scoping of requirements for the project deliverables.
- Improved the releases time by 10% by streamlining the process between the development and quality handoffs.

## **Software Engineer, Monetization**

eBay, San Jose, CA

*June 2020 – September 2021* 

- Architected and executed the implementation of Automation Framework by utilizing cypress.
- Implemented RESTFUL APIs to facilitate the overall regression.
- Scoped and estimated the timelines for the deliverables related to the Automation framework.
- Framework implemented is adapted across the teams in the Monetization org.
- Improved overall time of regression by 60%, which in turn reduced overhead time taken for each release by 15%.

# **Software Engineer, Identity**

eBay, San Jose, CA

September 2019 – May 2020

- Contributed towards eBay's Payment 2.0 Initiative by implementing the requisite microservices and user authentication RESTFUL APIs.
- Maintained and migrated legacy applications related to user-onboarding.
- Implemented and maintained user interfaces related to the user-onboarding and migration flows.
- Collaborated with the dependent teams to facilitate the scoping and implementation of Payment 2.0 deliverables.
- Mentored junior developers on the eBay tools, processes and deployment strategies.

## Agile Team Lead/Lead Developer, Marketing technologies

eBay, Seattle, WA

*April 2016 – August 2019* 

- Architected the Email framework 'Espresso' which helps in displaying the personalized data for eBay user.
- Lead a team of 6 developers to facilitate the implementation and maintenance the Espresso framework.
- Supervised the Email communication operations across the countries with eBay Marketing footprint in AMER, EMEA and APAC.
- Coordinated with the Google's AMP framework team to scope the integration of AMP framework into eBay's email communications.
- Authored data personalization APIs for fueling the content personalization in the marketing email communications.
- Mentored team to adapt the usage of new frameworks in order to improve the efficiency by cancelling out the monotonous work involved.
- Analyzed and adapted the feedback loop from email engagement, conversion and scoped out the potential opportunities that could improve both.
- Coordinated the quality, operations of delivering 100 MM everyday across the world.

• Espresso framework and designs led to an improvement of overall engagement by 6% and conversion rate by 1.5%.

### Analyst, Google Maps

Google, Hyderabad, India

Feb 2013 - Jul 2014

- Evaluated the efficiency of Google's image processing algorithms in Maps.
- Improved the geocode accuracy by utilizing the Googles internal tools.
- Trained and mentored onboarded employees on tools and processes.

# **Projects**

### **Empty meeting room finder**

This is a IOT project focused on providing an accurate visual representation of empty rooms available across the floors in eBay office, my team of 2 installed wallet sized devices with sensors relaying the data of the temperature of the room and light visibility in the room and relayed to the parent server constantly in regular intervals, All the data is being utilized and accumulated in order to give a specific visual representation of the available Meeting room and also predict the availability of the meeting room. This project is named People's choice award for its usability.

## **Education**

#### Master of Science (M.S.) in Computer Science

Murray State University, Murray, KY August 2014 – December 2015

• Relevant Coursework: Software Development, Decision Support and Expert Systems, Data Management, Project Management, Data Management, Advanced Business Analytics.

## Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech) in Information Technology

JNTU Kakinada, Guntur, India May 2008 – July 2012

## **Skills**

Expert (★★★★★): Java, SQL, JavaScript, Git version control, HTML5, CSS, Springboot, Spring MVC, Maven, J2EE, CRM.

Advanced (★★★★☆): Cypress, Mochawesome, Jenkins, Mongo DB, Junit, Project Management,

Familiar (★★★☆★): System design, Selenium, C++, .NET

## **Honors & Awards**

- Outstanding Student of Murray State University in 2015, for mentoring the undergraduate students at the university.
- Student leadership award for organizing and leading the efforts towards IT's ELITE (a literary club).

### **Hobbies & interests**

Volunteering, Mentoring, Reading.